# 嗨喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 最近有很多粉丝在问这个青花椒怎么样去保存
Many fans have been asking how to preserve green Sichuan peppercorns
# 现在我拿的这一袋是我刚刚拆的
I just took these out from a bag
# 这个是已经放了大概有几个月的时间
which have been stored for a few months
# 已经冻上了冰块
Already frozen
# 这个青花椒的话它因为熟的时间比较特殊
Green Sichuan peppercorns ripen in a special season
# 然后把它摘下来了之后如果没有方法去保存很快它就干了
After harvesting, they will dry soon if not preserved properly
# 很快这个味道就挥发了
All the flavor will evaporate soon
# 这个花椒属于油性挥发的东西
as peppercorns are oil-soluble and volatile
# 就没有（鲜花椒的）味道了
So there's no flavor (of fresh peppercorns) any more
# 然后今天跟大家分享一下这个保存的一些方法
Today, I'd like to share some methods to preserve it
# 我们这个花椒现在像这样子抽完真空
As you see, these peppercorns are vacuum sealed
# 抽了真空之后就放在那个冰柜里面把它冻硬
Vacuum seal, and then store it in a freezer
# 冻硬了之后的话这个可以保存 最长可以保存一年半以上
It can be stored frozen for 1.5 years or longer
# 这个是我目前知道的保存的时间最长的
As far as I know, that's the longest preservation
# 如果不是长期保存
If it's not for a long term preservation
# 可以把它放到一个容器里面
we can put them in a container
# 倒上一些植物油
and pour some vegetable oil
# 然后再放到冰柜里面密封保存
Then seal it, and leave it in a freezer
# 这样子的话可以保存一个月到三个月之间
In this way, it can be stored for 1 to 3 months